Paul Finch Senior Strategist

pjfinch@gmail.com 07475570686 pjfinchcreative.com

Summary

With over 15 years' experience as a brand strategist and creative director for brands in marketing, communications, and advertising, I'm a strategic and creative specialist in customer and key stakeholder relationships.

I have created fully integrated brand campaigns for some of the industry's best advertising, PR, Digital, Experiential and Event agencies in global markets – in Australia Clemenger BBDO/ Traffik, Geometry Global, Jack Morton, George P Johnson, Fourth Wall, Weber Shandwick. In London Accenture, Imagination, Glimma, 542 Digital and Liberation Design. In the middle east LINKVIVA and Action Impact.

At Accenture London as Senior Strategist and Creative Director, I lead a team of eighteen in the creative team from 2D designers, web developers, motion graphics artists, illustrators, art directors and copywriters.

I have worked with global brands across a diverse range of industry categories such as tech brands Amazon, AWS, Google, YouTube, Samsung, Microsoft, Canon, Nikon. Luxury brands Penfolds, Rolls Royce, Mercedes, BMW. Automotive brands Toyota and Mazda. Global management consultants Accenture (in-house), EY. Travel and leisure giant Royal Caribbean. Telco's Telstra, Optus. FMCG brands Kraft, Nestle, Nespresso, Heinz, LEGO, and Coca Cola.

With a background in film for over 20 years, I understand how story works. A particular focus on ESG pathways and sustainability through analysis and data driven insights, enables me to deliver measurable success and drive growth for customers and key stakeholders now and into the future. I am thus an exceptional strategic and creative leader, storyteller, and collaborator.

Career History

Senior Strategist, Jan - Present 2023 LIBERATION BUILD London (Agency)

Brand & Marketing Strategy for Google Android EMEA retail campaigns for 2023 in UK, France, and Germany

Senior Strategist, July - November 2022 542 DIGITAL London (Agency)

Creative strategy, brand strategy, digital strategy (UX, UI) for World Gold Council website re-launch. Researching and benchmarking global industry category competitors, understanding global and regional end user behaviors and needs. Defining platform and product utility with website and integrated digital channels. Working with team of UX and UI designers plus full stack developers for execution of platform and product.

Senior Strategist/ Creative Director, Feb – June 2022 GLIMMA London (Agency)

Creative strategy and brand strategy for global last mile logistics company BORZO. Repositioning brand to launch internal comms campaign and public facing brand re launch.

Senior Strategist, Oct 2021 - Jan 2022 IMAGINATION London (Agency)

Creative strategy for global campaigns for Rolls Royce Motor Company.

Senior Strategist/ Creative Director, May 2020 - Oct 2021 LINKVIVA Dubai (Agency)

Creative strategy and creative direction for global campaigns plus LINKVIVA brand repositioning, website design and launch.

Senior Strategist, Jun 2019 -Mar 2020 Accenture London

Supporting the sales teams for European digital transformation new business pitches through integrated brand experience including digital and multimedia content. Utilising highly analytical strategic and creative approach of target brand core values to align with Accenture core values. Impact was conversion of new business pitching to acquired multi-million-dollar digital transformation projects which increased revenue for the Accenture sales business sector.

Strategist/ Creative Director, Jan 2019 - June 2019 Geometry Global Sydney (Agency)

Devising strategy and creative big idea to inform integrated global campaign to launch Lelepa Island in Vanuatu for Royal Caribbean. Integrated campaign devised through highly analytical approach to understand how far to push the limits of what's possible with the intersection of real-world experiences and digital technology to enhance the experience of the product through AR and VR.

Senior Strategist/ Creative Director, June - Dec 2018 Weber Shandwick Sydney (Agency)

Nespresso pitch win for Sydney flagship store launch 2018 campaign strategy + creative direction. Generate national awareness and engagement with the George Street store launch, by positioning the boutique as the living embodiment of Nespresso's sustainability story. Told in a sequence to mirror the boutique's ENGAGE, INVOLVE, EXPLORE zones the launch concept will bring a wide variety of Australian media, influencers, Sydney stakeholders, members and prospects on our global coffee journey.

Strategist/ Creative Director, Jan 2016 - Jan 2019 Fourth Wall Sydney (Agency)

Creative Director, production designer and art director for new business pitches and projects for:

2018 Won Optus Sales Kick Off 2019 three way pitch against leading Australian events agencies

2018 Won Sunglass Hut brand experience campaign launch 'House of Sun' summer 2018 to support 12-month media campaign

YouTube Creator Summit 2017 and Vidcon 2018 both targeted at youth/ millennial consumers

2017 Won Optus three-way competitive pitch for consumer facing brand experience projects

2016 Won BCG/Digital Ventures three-way competitive pitch for Digital Ventures brand new office space launch in The Rocks

March 2016 Won Google/YouTube and remains Fourth Wall's biggest client.

Strategist/ Creative Director, Jan 2015 - Jan 2016 Jack Morton Sydney (Agency)

Creative Director, Production Designer, Art Director for:

Microsoft Windows 10 global media launch event, Australia region

Targeted at youth/ millennial 'superfans'

Globally recognised by Microsoft head office in New York as a benchmark in exciting and immersive superfan experience

Microsoft APC 2015, Gold Coast, Australia \$2mill budget, 2,000 IT professionals and web developers 3-day event Telstra L&P 2015 Darwin, Australia \$2mill budget 1,500 delegates franchisee owners 4-day conference Won NSW Planning Dept corporate plan launch 2015 4-way pitch for 10 digital content videos for both internal and consumer Devised strategy, wrote treatment and scripts, set to direct

Strategist/ Creative Director, Jul - Dec 2014 LINKVIVA Dubai (Agency)

Creative Director for new business pitch:
Won Lenovo Vibe Smartphones Launch 2015 Dubai, UAE.
3-way competitive pitch for Brand Experience campaign
Series of activations targeted at youth/ millennials style pioneers
Focus on the arts and creativity

LOVE IS NOW Feature Film Jul - Dec 2014 Sydney

Production Designer for Australian feature film 'LOVE IS NOW', Directed by Jim Lounsbury, Produced by Behren Schulz, Line Producer David Lightfoot, Cinematography by Tony Jennings. Distributed at Hoyts Cinema's nationwide by Universal Pictures

Creative Director, Jan 2013 - Jan 2014 George P Johnson Sydney (Agency)

Creative Director/ Production Designer for
Toyota National Dealer's Meeting and National Sales Conference 2014
\$3mill budget, 450 dealers and partners 4-day conference Dreamworld and Jupiter's Casino, Gold Coast QLD

AROUND THE BLOCK Feature Film July 2012 - Jan 2013 Sydney

Art Director for Australian feature film starring Christina Ricci, Jack Thompson. Directed by Sarah Spillane, produced by Brian Rosen and Su Armstrong (Good Will Hunting).

Creative Strategist/Creative Director, Apr 2011 - Jun 2012 Traffik Marketing/ Clemenger BBDO Sydney (Agency)

Creative Strategist/ Creative Director - permanent role.

Won new business pitch for Samsung, Traffik's biggest client to date. Also won new business pitches for Kraft - Cadbury's, Oreo's, and Mazda.

Creative Strategist/Creative Director, Jan 2010 - Apr 2011 C4 Photon Group Sydney (Agency)

- 2011 Microsoft Tech Lounge at Sydney University
- 2010 Hotel Expo Melbourne Sony Entertainment & Security Technology new business pitch
- Socceroos Farewell Football Match MCG Sony Bravia 3D TV new business pitch
- FIFA 2010 World Cup Fanfest Hospitality Darling Harbour Sony Bravia 3D TV

Creative Director, Sept 20008 - Dec 2009 Jack Morton Worldwide Sydney (Agency)

Sony Bravia HDTV Media Launch Event 2009.

Key Skills

- Marketing + Communications
- Brand & Marketing Strategy
- CX strategy
- Digital Strategy UX, UI
- Creative Direction
- Integrated Campaigns
- Leadership and management
- Social Media
- Digital Video Content/ Film

Web Profiles

• <u>pjfinchcreative.com</u>

Education History

- o BA (Hons) Architecture
- University of Greenwich

Interests & Hobbies

 Drawing, painting, photography, surfing, snowboarding, skateboarding, road cycling, cricket, golf, cooking, travel